Preliminary Inventory of the Victor T. Le Vine Papers, 1954-1961
Hoover Institution Archives
Victor T. Le Vine Papers,
1954-1961
72003
Le Vine, Victor T.
2 manuscript boxes (.8 linear feet)
Hoover Institution Archives Stanford, California 94305-6010
Pamphlets, campaign literature, clippings, and other printed matter, relating to the political development of the Cameroons. Used as research material for the book by V. T. Le Vine, The Cameroons: From Mandate to Independence (1964)
Administrative Information
Access
Collection open for research.
The Hoover Institution Archives only allows access to copies of audiovisual items. To listen to sound recordings or to view videos or films during your visit, please contact the Archives at least two working days before your arrival. We will then advise you of the accessibility of the material you wish to see or hear. Please note that not all audiovisual material is immediately accessible.
Acquisition Information
Acquired by the Hoover Institution Archives in 1972.
Accruals
Materials may have been added to the collection since this finding aid was prepared. To determine if this has occurred, find the collection in Stanford University's online catalog at http://searchworks.stanford.edu/. Materials have been added to the collection if the number of boxes listed in the online catalog is larger than the number of boxes listed in this finding aid.
Access Points
Africa.; Cameroon.; Cameroon--Politics and government.
Container List
- Bebey-Eyidi, Dr. Marcel, pamphlet publications (Box 1)
- British Camerouns (North)
- British Camerouns (South)
  - Political parties
  - Southern Information Service, press releases, 1959-1961
- Cameroun election of 1961
  - Reports and regulations
  - Campaign literature
  - Campaign posters and leaflets
  - Clippings
- Cameroun government press releases
- Moumie, Felix-Roland (President of Cameroun), letter to V. T. Levine, April 28, 1960 (Box 2)
- Parti des Democrates Camerounais, clippings
- Representative institutions
  - General
  - Constitution of Cameroun, February 21, 1960
  - Who's Who in Southern Cameroun Legislature, 1954-1961
- Union Camerounaise, publications
- Union des Populations du Cameroun
  - Proclamations and press releases
  - Publications and printed matter
- Miscellaneous printed matter